Sculpture Photograph Collection: Italy-United States
Yale University Arts Library
Sculpture Photograph Collection: Italy-United States
1900-2005
VRC 5.3
Yale University Arts Library
46.6
113 boxes (Boxes 153-265 of 265)
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of sculpture. This section covers the later medieval to modern periods in European and other countries alphabetically from Italy to Switzerland. Also includes North American sculpture (United States and Canada). Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Conditions Governing Access
These materials are stored offsite at the Library Shelving Facility. For access to the materials, please make a request at the Art & Architecture Library.
Arrangement
In this section, the photographs are arranged by country. Subdivided by artist.
Scope and Contents
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of sculpture. This section covers the later medieval to modern periods in European and other countries alphabetically from Italy to Switzerland. Also includes North American sculpture (United States and Canada). Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Sculpture; Photographs; Reproductions
- Italy (Box 153)
  - Anonymous Artists., 483 (Box 153)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes three folders of miscellaneous clippings.
    - Miscellaneous works., 10 (Box 153)
    - IX-X Century., 7 (Box 153)
    - XI Century., 24 (Box 153)
      - Miscellaneous works., 6 (Box 153)
      - Bronze doors., 18 (Box 153)
    - XII Century., 66 (Box 153)
      Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings.
      - Miscellaneous works., 15 (Box 153)
      - Bronze doors., 31 (Box 154)
      - Pulpits., 20 (Box 154)
        - Miscellaneous works., 17 (Box 154)
        - Maestro Niccolo., 2 (Box 154)
    - XIII Century., 38 (Box 155)
    - XIV Century., 61 (Box 156)
      - Miscellaneous works., 24 (Box 156)
      - Pulpits., 4 (Box 156)
      - Tombs., 33 (Box 156)
    - XV Century., 178 (Box 157)
      - Miscellaneous works., 62 (Box 157)
      - Busts., 26 (Box 158)
      - Arco d'Alfonso I d'Aragona., 27 (Box 158)
      - Madonna and child., 21 (Box 159)
      - Tombs and Monuments., 42 (Box 159)
    - XVI Century., 54 (Box 160)
    - XVII-XVIII Century., 25 (Box 161)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 22 (Box 161)
      - Varallo and Varese., 3 (Box 161)
    - XIX-XX Century., 19 (Box 161)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 13 (Box 161)
      - Genoa, Campo Santo., 6 (Box 161)
  - Artists, Known., 3551 (Box 162)
    - A, 115 (Box 162)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 15 (Box 162)
        - Agrate, Marco, XVI C., 1 (Box 162)
        - Alberghetti, Alfonso, XVI C., 1 (Box 162)
        - Alberti, Leone Battista, 1404-1484., 3 (Box 162)
        - Ambrogio da Milano, active 1472-1516/7., 1 (Box 162)
        - Andrea da Firenzi, active 1388-1453., 1 (Box 162)
        - Andreotti, Libero, 1875-1933., 2 (Box 162)
        - Angelini, Giuseppe, 1735-1811., 1 (Box 162)
        - Antonio da Milano, active c.1474-1475., 1 (Box 162)
        - Aprile, Francesco, XVII C., 1 (Box 162)
        - Arnoldi, Alberto, active 1351-1364., 2 (Box 162)
        - Auteri, Michele, 1838-1918., 1 (Box 162)
      - Individual Artists., 100 (Box 162)
        - Agostino di Giovanni, XIII C., 4 (Box 162)
        - Algardi, Alessandro, 1602-1654., 19 (Box 162)
        - Amadeo, Giovanni Antonio, 1447-1522., 10 (Box 162)
        - Ammannati, Bartolomeo, 1511-1592., 12 (Box 162)
        - Antelami, Benedetto, c.1150-1233., 14 (Box 163)
        - L'Antico, c.1460-1528., 11 (Box 163)
          Also known as Pier Jacopo Alari Bonacolsi.
        - Antonio Federighi, 1420-1490., 19 (Box 163)
        - Arnolfo di Cambio, 1260-1302., 6 (Box 163)
        - Aspetti, Tiziano, 1565-1607., 5 (Box 163)
    - B, 379 (Box 164)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 37 (Box 164)
        - Babaccio, Antonio P., 1351-1435., 1 (Box 164)
        - Balla, Giacomo, 1871-1958., 1 (Box 164)
        - Baratta, Francesco, -1666., 1 (Box 164)
        - Barili, Giovanni, and family, XVI C., 3 (Box 164)
        - Bartolini, Lorenzo, 1777-1850., 1 (Box 164)
        - Barzaghi, Francesco, 1839-1892., 1 (Box 164)
        - Begarelli, Antonio, 1499-1565., 3 (Box 164)
        - Belli, Valerio, 1468-1546., 2 (Box 164)
        - Benzoni, Giovanni Maria, 1809-1873., 1 (Box 164)
        - Bergamasco, Guglielmo and Giovanni B. da Carona, active 1529-1533., 1 (Box 164)
        - Bernardi, Giovanni dei, 1496-1553., 2 (Box 164)
        - Bernini, Pietro, 1562-1629., 2 (Box 164)
        - Bernardi, Giovanni, da Castel, 1496-1553., 1 (Box 164)
        - Boccioni, Umberto, 1882-1916., 1 (Box 164)
        - Bologna, Giovanni da, 1524-1608., 1 (Box 164)
        - Bonino da Campione, active 1340-1397., 3 (Box 164)
        - Bottiglieri, Pagano, XVII C.?., 1 (Box 164)
        - Bracci, Pietro, 1700-1773., 1 (Box 164)
        - Bregno, Andrea, 1421-1506., 1 (Box 164)
        - Brescia, Andrea d'Alessandro, active 1570., 2 (Box 164)
        - Briosco, Benedetto, 1483-1506., 1 (Box 164)
        - Buggiano, 1412-1462., 1 (Box 164)
          Also known as Andrea de Lazzaro Cavalcanti.
        - Buglione, Benedetto, ?., 1 (Box 164)
        - Buon, Bartolomeo, 1410-1464., 2 (Box 164)
        - Burri, Alberto, 1915-., 1 (Box 164)
        - Buzi, I., XVIII C.?, 1 (Box 164)
      - Individual Artists., 342 (Box 164)
        - Banco, Nanni d'Antonio di, c.1383-1471., 30 (Box 164)
          - Miscellaneous works., 17 (Box 164)
          - Four crowned saints., 12 (Box 164)
        - Bandinelli, Baccio, 1493-1560., 4 (Box 165)
        - Bandini, Giovanni, 1540-1599., 4 (Box 165)
        - Bardi, Giovanni d'Antonio Minelli de, 1460-1527., 4 (Box 165)
        - Barisano da Trani, active c.1180., 16 (Box 165)
        - Bellano, Bartollomeo, 1430-1498., 9 (Box 165)
        - Benedetto da Maiano, 1442-1497., 60 (Box 166)
          - Miscellaneous locations., 22 (Box 166)
          - Florence., 27 (Box 166)
            - Miscellaneous locations., 13 (Box 166)
            - S. Croce., 14 (Box 166)
          - Paris., 6 (Box 166)
          - Siena., 5 (Box 166)
        - Benedetto da Rovezzano, 1474-c.1552., 11 (Box 167)
        - Bernini, Giovanni Lorenzo, 1598-1680., 124 (Box 167)
          - Miscellaneous locations., 14 (Box 167)
          - London., 10 (Box 167)
          - Rome., 85 (Box 167)
            - Miscellaneous locations., 18 (Box 168)
            - Borghese Gallery., 24 (Box 168)
            - Piazza Navona., 6 (Box 168)
            - S. Maria della Vittoria., 30 (Box 168)
            - S. Peter's., 7 (Box 168)
          - Versailles., 6 (Box 168)
          - Washington., 9 (Box 168)
        - Bertoldo di Giovanni, c.1430-1491., 9 (Box 169)
        - Boccioni, Umberto, 1882-1916., 3 (Box 169)
        - Bregno, Andrea, 1421-1506., 9 (Box 169)
        - Briosco, Andrea, 1470-1532., 32 (Box 169)
          Also known as Il Riccio.
        - Brunelleschi, Filippo, 1377-1446., 15 (Box 169)
        - Buora, Giovanni, 1445/55-1515/19., 4 (Box 169)
          Works may be by Domenico Duca.
        - Bussola, Dionigi, 1612-1687., 1 (Box 169)
          See also: Sculpture, Italy, XVII C., Varese, Sacro Monte.
        - Busti, Agostino, 1483-1548., 4 (Box 169)
    - C, 266 (Box 170)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 26 (Box 170)
        - Cabianca, Vincenza, 1827-1902., 2 (Box 170)
        - Caccini, Giovanni, 1562-1612., 1 (Box 170)
        - Calieri, Gabrieli, 1568-1631., 1 (Box 170)
        - Cambio, Arnolfo di, 1260-1302., 4 (Box 170)
        - Campagna, Girolamo, 1552-c.1623., 2 (Box 170)
        - Capponi, Luigi, XV-XVI C., 2 (Box 170)
        - Caprioli, L., XVII C.?, 1 (Box 170)
        - Castelli, Domenico, active 1621-1658., 1 (Box 170)
        - Cavalli, Bartolommeo, XV C., 2 (Box 170)
        - Cavallini, Francesco, active 1645-1686., 1 (Box 170)
        - Cecioni, Adriano, active XIX C., 1 (Box 170)
        - Celebrano, Francesco, 1729-1814., 1 (Box 170)
        - Ceroli, Mario, 1938-., 1 (Box 170)
        - Cesar, 1921-., 1 (Box 170)
        - Cigoli, Ludovico Cardi, 1559-1613., 1 (Box 170)
        - Consagra, Pietro, 1920-., 1 (Box 170)
        - Conte, Pino, 1915-., 1 (Box 170)
        - Corradini, Antonio, active 1695-1752., 1 (Box 170)
        - Costoli, Aristodemo, 1803-1871., 1 (Box 170)
      - Individual Artists., 240 (Box 170)
        - Canova, Antonio, 1757-1822., 64 (Box 170)
          - Locations not noted., 7 (Box 170)
          - Miscellaneous cities., 36 (Box 170)
          - Rome., 21 (Box 170)
            - Miscellaneous locations., 7 (Box 170)
            - Vatican., 14 (Box 170)
        - Cattaneo, Danese, 1509-1573., 4 (Box 171)
        - Cellini, Benvenuto, 1500-1572., 71 (Box 171)
          - Miscellaneous locations., 20 (Box 171)
          - El Escorial., 16 (Box 171)
          - Florence., 27 (Box 171)
          - Vienna., 8 (Box 171)
        - Ceracchi, Guiseppi, 1751-1802., 4 (Box 172)
        - Cione, Andrea di, 1308-1368., 29 (Box 172)
          Also known as Orcagna.
        - Ciuffagni, Bernardo, 1381-1456., 15 (Box 172)
        - Civitali, Matteo, 1436-1501., 38 (Box 173)
          - Miscellaneous locations., 12 (Box 173)
          - Lucca., 26 (Box 173)
        - Cortona, Urbana da, -1504., 5 (Box 173)
        - Cosmati family, XII-XIV C., 5 (Box 173)
          Includes Lorenzo, Giacomo, and Giovanni.
        - Cozzarelli, Giacomo di Bartolomeo, 1453-1515., 5 (Box 173)
    - D, 748 (Box 174)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 10 (Box 174)
        - Dalmata, Giovani, 1440-1509., 2 (Box 174)
        - Daniele da Volterra, 1509-1566., 1 (Box 174)
        - Danti, Vicenzo, 1530-1576., 2 (Box 174)
        - Da Vinci, Pierino, XVI C., 2 (Box 174)
        - Dazzi, Arturo, 1882-1966., 1 (Box 174)
        - De Fabris, School of, XIX C., 1 (Box 174)
        - Della Bitta and Zappala, XIX-XX C., 1 (Box 174)
      - Individual Artists., 738 (Box 174)
        - Desiderio da Settignano, 1428-1464., 177 (Box 174)
          - Miscellaneous locations., 15 (Box 174)
          - Florence., 101 (Box 174)
            - Miscellaneous locations., 11 (Box 174)
            - S. Croce, tomb of C. Marsuppini., 90 (Box 174)
              - Overviews., 6 (Box 174)
              - Base., 11 (Box 175)
              - Effigy., 4 (Box 175)
              - Lunette relief/Madonna and child and angels., 13 (Box 175)
              - Putti., 13 (Box 175)
              - Urn with pedestal., 12 (Box 175)
              - Youths bearing garland., 11 (Box 175)
              - Sectional views., 6 (Box 175)
              - General details., 14 (Box 175)
          - Paris., 14 (Box 176)
          - Washington., 25 (Box 176)
          - Berlin., 22 (Box 176)
        - Donatello, 1386-1466., 477 (Box 177)
          - Miscellaneous works., 7 (Box 177)
          - Miscellaneous locations., 22 (Box 177)
          - Berlin., 13 (Box 177)
          - Florence., 266 (Box 177)
            - Miscellaneous locations., 1 (Box 177)
            - Baptistry., 12 (Box 177)
            - Cathedral Museum (Museo del Opera del Duomo)., 53 (Box 178)
              - Miscellaneous works., 12 (Box 178)
              - Jeremiah/Habakkuk., 15 (Box 178)
              - Cantoria., 26 (Box 178)
            - National Museum (Bargello)., 60 (Box 179)
              - Miscellaneous works., 26 (Box 179)
              - David (bronze)., 15 (Box 179)
              - S. George (from Or San Michele), 8 (Box 179)
              - Portrait busts., 11 (Box 179)
            - Or San Michele., 17 (Box 180)
            - Piazza della Signoria., 15 (Box 180)
              - Miscellaneous works., 1 (Box 180)
              - Judith and Holofernes., 14 (Box 180)
            - S. Croce., 34 (Box 180)
              - Miscellaneous works., 14 (Box 180)
              - Annunciation tabernacle., 20 (Box 180)
            - S. Lorenzo., 74 (Box 181)
              - Miscellaneous works., 11 (Box 181)
              - Roundels., 14 (Box 181)
              - North pulpit., 30 (Box 181)
              - South pulpit., 19 (Box 181)
          - Padua., 90 (Box 182)
            - Gattamelata., 13 (Box 182)
            - S. Antonio., 77 (Box 182)
              - Miscellaneous works., 4 (Box 182)
              - High Altar (of San Antonio)., 73 (Box 182)
                - Schematics and overviews., 9 (Box 182)
                - Angels of Music., 10 (Box 182)
                - Relief scenes., 30 (Box 182)
                - Saints., 24 (Box 182)
          - Paris., 12 (Box 183)
          - Prato., 11 (Box 183)
          - Siena., 31 (Box 183)
            - Miscellaneous works., 14 (Box 183)
            - Faith and Hope., 9 (Box 183)
            - Feast of Herod., 8 (Box 183)
          - Washington., 16 (Box 184)
          - Attributed to Donatello., 9 (Box 184)
        - Dossena, Alceo, 1878-1936., 3 (Box 184)
        - Duccio, Agostino di, 1418-1498., 77 (Box 185)
          - Miscellaneous locations., 15 (Box 185)
          - Perugia., 20 (Box 185)
            - Miscellaneous locations., 4 (Box 185)
            - Ss. Andrea and Bernardino., 16 (Box 185)
          - Rimini, Tempio Malatestiano., 22 (Box 185)
        - Dupre, Giovanni, 1817-1882., 4 (Box 185)
    - F, 110 (Box 186)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 22 (Box 186)
        - Fabro, Luciano, 1936-., 1 (Box 186)
        - Fancelli, Giacomo, 1619-1671., 1 (Box 186)
        - Fasolato, Agostino, active 1741-1753., 1 (Box 186)
        - Fedi, Pio, 1815-1892., 2 (Box 186)
        - Ferrari, Ettore, 1848-1929., 1 (Box 186)
        - Ferrata, Ercole, 1610-1686., 2 (Box 186)
        - Ferrucci, Andrea, 1465-1526., 2 (Box 186)
        - Fiamberti, Tommaso, active 1480-1524., 2 (Box 186)
        - Fiorentino, Adriano, active XV C., 1 (Box 186)
        - Fontana, G., active 1593-1627 (?)., 1 (Box 186)
          Work done with C. Maderno.
        - Fontana, Lucio, 1899-1968., 3 (Box 186)
        - Formiggini, active 1515-1530., 2 (Box 186)
        - Franca-Villa, Pietro, 1553-1615., 1 (Box 186)
        - Franceschi, Emilio, 1839-1890., 1 (Box 186)
        - Franchina, Nino, XX C., 2 (Box 186)
      - Individual Artists., 88 (Box 186)
        - Faggi, Alfeo, XX C., 3 (Box 186)
        - Ferrucci, Francesco di Simone, 1437-1493., 12 (Box 186)
        - Fetti, Giovanni, active 1355-1386., 1 (Box 186)
        - Filarete, Antonio, 1400-1469., 22 (Box 186)
        - Finelli, Giuliano, 1601/2-1657., 5 (Box 187)
        - Fiorentino, Jacopo, -1526., 4 (Box 187)
        - Foggini, Giovanni Battista, 1652-1737., 29 (Box 187)
        - Francesco di Giorgio Martini, 1435-1502., 12 (Box 187)
    - G, 352 (Box 187)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 25 (Box 187)
        - Gaddi, Gaddo, 1260-1333?, 1 (Box 187)
        - Gaggini, Domenico active 1448-1492., 2 (Box 187)
          One photo is "Family of" or "School of".
        - Gai, Antonio, 1686-1769., 1 (Box 187)
        - Gano da Siena, active c.1303, died c.1318., 1 (Box 187)
        - Gemito, Vincenzo, 1852-1928., 2 (Box 187)
        - Geremia, Cristoforo di, c.1410-c.1475., 1 (Box 187)
        - Ghiberti, Vittorio, 1416-1496., 1 (Box 187)
        - Giamoti, Dominique S., XVII C., 1 (Box 187)
        - Giovanni da Palermo, Fra, ?., 1 (Box 187)
        - Giovanni da Pisa, died before 1460., 1 (Box 187)
        - Giovanni da Santa Croce, XV C., 1 (Box 187)
        - Giovanni di Balduccio, 1290-1350., 3 (Box 187)
        - Giovanni di Francesco d'Arezzo, active 1369-1375., 2 (Box 187)
        - Giovanni di Stefano, active 1446-before 1506., 2 (Box 187)
        - Giovanozzo e Alberti, XV C.?, 1 (Box 187)
        - Giuliani, Giovanni, 1663-1774., 1 (Box 187)
        - Gruamonte da Pisa, Medieval., 1 (Box 187)
        - Guardi, Andrea, active 1451-1470., 1 (Box 187)
        - Guarnerio, Pierandrea, XVII C., 1 (Box 187)
      - Individual Artists., 327 (Box 187)
        - Gagini, Antonio, 1478-1536., 7 (Box 187)
        - Ghiberti, Lorenzo, 1378-1455/6., 208 (Box 188)
          - Miscellaneous works., 13 (Box 188)
          - Florence., 183 (Box 188)
            - Miscellaneous works., 20 (Box 188)
            - East doors, Baptistry., 107 (Box 188)
              - Overviews., 8 (Box 188)
              - Inner frame., 38 (Box 188)
              - Outer frame (details)., 18 (Box 189)
              - Panels., 43 (Box 189)
                - Panels 1&2: Story of Creation, Story of Cain and Abel., 10 (Box 189)
                - Panels 3&4: Story of Noah, Story of Abraham and Isaac., 7 (Box 189)
                - Panels 5&6: Story of Jacod and Essau, Story of Joseph., 13 (Box 189)
                - Panels 7&8: Story of Moses, Story of Joshua., 6 (Box 189)
                - Panels 9&10: David and Goliath, Solomon and the Queen of Sheba., 7 (Box 189)
            - North doors, Baptistry., 49 (Box 190)
              - Overviews and decorative details., 13 (Box 190)
              - Panels., 36 (Box 190)
                - Panels 1-8., 9 (Box 190)
                Includes Ss. Ambrose, Jerome, Gregory, Augustine, John, Matthew, Luke, Mark.
                - Panels 9-18:, 14 (Box 190)
                Includes Nativity, Adoration of the Magi, Dispute in the Temple, Baptism of Christ, Temptation of Christ, Driving the Moneychangers from the Temple, Walking on the Water, Transfiguration, Raising of Lazarus.
                - Panels 19-28., 13 (Box 190)
                Includes Entry into Jerusalem, Last Supper, Christ on the Mount of Olives, Betrayal of Christ, Christ before Pilate, Flagellation, Road to Calvary, Crucifixion, Resurrection, Descent of the Holy Spirit.
            - South doors, Baptistry., 7 (Box 191)
          - Forgeries., 8 (Box 191)
        - Giacomo, Bernardino da, active 1543., 5 (Box 191)
        - Giovanni d'Ambrogio, active 1384-1418., 2 (Box 191)
        - Giovanni da Bologna, 1524-1608., 79 (Box 191)
          - Miscellaneous locations., 25 (Box 191)
          - Bologna., 5 (Box 191)
          - Florence., 40 (Box 192)
            - Miscellaneous locations., 34 (Box 192)
            - Loggia dei Lanzi., 6 (Box 192)
          - Washington, D.C., 9 (Box 192)
        - Giovanni and Pacio da Firenze, XIV C., 5 (Box 192)
        - Giovanni da Verona, Fra, 1457-1525., 4 (Box 192)
        - Giuliano da San Gallo, 1445-1516., 4 (Box 192)
        - Guglielmo da Pisa, c.1235-1311., 2 (Box 192)
        - Guidi, Jacopo di Piero, active 1379-1405., 4 (Box 192)
          Some works with Giovanni Fetti.
        - Guido Bigarelli da Como, XIII C., 7 (Box 192)
    - H, I, J, K, L, 134 (Box 193)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 19 (Box 193)
        - Iacobello e Pier Paolo, XVI C., 1 (Box 193)
        - Isaia da Pisa, active 1450., 1 (Box 193)
        - Kounellis, Jannis, 1936-., 1 (Box 193)
        - Lanfrani, Jacopo, active c.1343-1367., 3 (Box 193)
        - Lastricati, Zanobi, 1508-1590., 1 (Box 193)
        - Leoni, Leone, 1509-1590., 3 (Box 193)
        - Lombardo, Antonio, c.1458-1516., 2 (Box 193)
        - Lombardo, Girolamo, 1504-1590., 1 (Box 193)
        - Lombardo, Tommaso, active c.1550., 1 (Box 193)
        - Longhena, Baldassare, 1598-1682., 1 (Box 193)
        - Lorenzo Lorenzetto, 1490-1541., 1 (Box 193)
        - Lotti, Lorenzo, 1490-1541., 2 (Box 193)
        - Lucchesi, Bruno, 1926-., 1 (Box 193)
      - Individual Artists., 115 (Box 193)
        - Lardero, Berto, 1911-., 4 (Box 193)
        - Laurana, Francesco, c.1425-1502., 33 (Box 193)
          - Miscellaneous locations., 21 (Box 193)
          - Berlin., 11 (Box 193)
        - Leonardo da Vinci, 1452-1519., 7 (Box 193)
        - Leopardi, Alessandro, 1447-1522., 9 (Box 194)
        - Lombardo, Pietro, 1435-1515., 22 (Box 194)
          Some works are done with his son, Tullio Lombardo.
          - Miscellaneous locations., 5 (Box 194)
          - Venice., 17 (Box 194)
        - Lombardo, Tullio, c.1455-1532., 40 (Box 194)
          - Miscellaneous locations., 7 (Box 194)
          - New York., 11 (Box 194)
          - Venice., 22 (Box 194)
    - M, 498 (Box 195)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 20 (Box 195)
        - Maestro dei Mesi di Ferrara, XIII C., 1 (Box 195)
        - Magni, Pietro, 1817-1877., 1 (Box 195)
        - Manni, Giannicola di Paolo, c.1460-1544., 1 (Box 195)
        - Maraini, Antonio, 1886-1863., 1 (Box 195)
        - Marino, Raffaele, 1868-., 1 (Box 195)
        - Marrina, Lorenzo, 1476-1534., 1 (Box 195)
        - Martini, Arturo, 1889-1947., 3 (Box 195)
        - Maso di Bartolommeo, 1406-1456., 4 (Box 195)
        - Mastroianni, Umberto, 1910-., 1 (Box 195)
        - Mazzuola, G. 1644-1725., 1 (Box 195)
        - Menghini, Niccolo, 1610-1655., 1 (Box 195)
        - Mirko, 1910-., 1 (Box 195)
          Also known as Mirko Basaldella.
        - Mitoraj, Migor, 1944-., 1 (Box 195)
        - Moderno, active XVI C., 1 (Box 195)
        - Montelupo, Baccio da, 1469-1535., 1 (Box 195)
      - Individual Artists., 478 (Box 195)
        - Maderno, Stefano, 1576-1636., 4 (Box 195)
        - Maini, Giovanni Battista, 1690-1752., 5 (Box 195)
        - Maitani, Lorenzo, c.1275-1330., 28 (Box 195)
        - Manzo, Giacomo, 1908-., 21 (Box 195)
        - Mariano, Lorenzo, 1476-1531., 4 (Box 196)
        - Marini, Marino, 1901-1980., 28 (Box 196)
        - Masegne, Jacob delle, School of, XV C., 16 (Box 196)
        - Masuccio, the Younger, 1291-1388., 5 (Box 196)
        - Mazzoni, Guido, 1450-1518., 7 (Box 196)
        - Michelangelo Buonarotti, 1475-1564., 209 (Box 196)
          Includes two folders of miscellaneous clippings.
          - Miscellaneous locations., 13 (Box 197)
          - Bruges., 11 (Box 197)
          - Florence., 126 (Box 197)
            - Miscellaneous locations., 14 (Box 197)
            - Accademia., 23 (Box 197)
              - Miscellaneous works., 13 (Box 197)
              - David., 10 (Box 197)
            - Bargello (National Museum)., 25 (Box 198)
            - Cathedral., 8 (Box 198)
            - S. Lorenzo., 56 (Box 198)
              - Miscellaneous works., 7 (Box 198)
            - Tomb of Giuliano de'Medeci., 24 (Box 198)
            - Tomb of Lorenzo de'Medici., 25 (Box 198)
          - Milan., 9 (Box 199)
          - Paris., 12 (Box 199)
          - Rome., 38 (Box 199)
            - Miscellaneous locations., 3 (Box 199)
            - S. Peter's., 19 (Box 199)
            - S. Pietro in Vincoli., 16 (Box 199)
        - Michelozzo di Bartolommeo, 1396-1472., 46 (Box 200)
          - Miscellaneous locations., 7 (Box 200)
          - Florence., 20 (Box 200)
          - Montepulciano., 19 (Box 200)
        - Mino da Fiesole, 1430/31-1484., 80 (Box 201)
          - Miscellaneous locations., 26 (Box 201)
          - Florence., 35 (Box 201)
            - Miscellaneous locations., 12 (Box 201)
            - Badia., 13 (Box 201)
            - Bargello (National Museum)., 10 (Box 202)
          - Rome., 13 (Box 202)
          - Washington., 6 (Box 202)
        - Mochi, Francesco, 1580-1654., 4 (Box 202)
        - Modigliani, Amadeo, 1884-1920., 11 (Box 202)
        - Montorsoli, Giovanni Angelo, 1507-1563., 4 (Box 202)
        - Moscha, Simone and Francesco, XVI C., 6 (Box 202)
          Name also given as Moschino.
    - N, 46 (Box 203)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 3 (Box 203)
        - Niccolo, Piero de, -1451., 1 (Box 203)
        - Niccolo dei Conti, active 1556-1574., 1 (Box 203)
        - Niccolo di Bartolommeo, active 1272., 1 (Box 203)
      - Individual Artists., 43 (Box 203)
        - Nanni di Bartolo, active 1419-1451., 10 (Box 203)
        - Neroccio di Bartolommeo di Benedetto dei Landi, 1447-1500., 7 (Box 203)
        - Niccolo d'Angelo, XII C., 4 (Box 203)
          Works done with Pietro Vassalletto.
        - Niccolo dell'Arco, active 1463-1494., 16 (Box 203)
        - Nola, Giovanni Merliano da, 1478-1560., 6 (Box 203)